Yiannis Papadopoulos

Socratous 72 st, Chaidari, 12462

Phone: +30 6947 77 0968 | Email: iann2048@gmail.com LinkedIn: YiannisPapadopoulos Portfolio: Link

Creative and proactive, believing in user centric design that focuses on content and optimizes user experience.

Through my experience on digital marketing teams, I became aware of my talent to keep teams together, focused on the goal, while my past as a freelancer fuels my proactive work ethic.

Skills

Technical: Photoshop / Illustrator / After Effects / InDesign / Miro / Invision / Figma / Bootstrap / HTML & CSS conversational

UX: User research / Usability testings / Qualitative interviews / User empathy / Competitors analysis / Heuristic Evaluation / Visual Prototyping & Wireframing / Storyboarding / A/B testings / Accessibility Testings / 5sec Testings

UI: Visual hierarchy / Layouts & grid systems / Typography / Color theory / Animation / **Other Skills:** Visual storytelling / Illustration & Character design / Branding / Photo editing

Relevant Experience

UI/UX Designer 2021 – 2023

Whitehat Inbound Marketing Agency

Athens, Greece

- Part of a creative team of 3 members (head of marketing, a developer and myself).
- Website responsive design applying guidelines & ux best practices.
- Design responsive landing pages for targeted audiences.
- Design social media posts for digital campaigns.
- Created visual assets for newsletter campaigns launched in the Hubspot platform.
- Branding (Creating documented brand studies and guidelines).

Graphic / Digital Designer

2018 - 2020

Medi Jeunesse

Athens, Greece

- Part of a digital marketing team of 3 members, created content for digital campaigns (visual assets: static, gif, video for posts and ads) posted on a daily basis.
- Designed marketing collaterals and updated website content (slider ,article and offer banners) increasing the website engagement.
- Created visual assets for newsletter campaigns through mailchimp. All the above within a framework of upgrading the brand identity on a more coherent and corporate level.

- Stakeholders praised the initiative to create documents of concrete and accurate brand guidelines.
- The new customers acquired through digital channels increased from 10% to 45% of the total number of new customers.

Graphic / Digital Designer Redirect Digital Agency

2017-2017

Athens, Greece

- Part of a creative team of 4 members (2 designers & 2 copywriters), designed social media posts for various brands following their guidelines
- Updated website visuals for various brands.
- Backing up with critical research and study the business proposal that won for the team the contract of managing the Netflix Greece social media.

Graphic / Digital Designer Sieben Itd (IT Company)

2015-2017

Athens, Greece

- Designing and editing videos in After Effects,
- Designing mobile application layout, vector icons, web page layouts, web banners, illustrations, business cards, various marketing collaterals.

Projects

We Care for Paws Foundation (WCPF) UX UI Group Project https://yiannispapadopoulos.github.io/casestudy/

Team's goal was to redesign the Foundation website in order to help visitors donate and search effectively for an animal to adopt, while reestablishing the site's sense of trust.

- Responsibilities: Structuring interview plan / Coordinating tests & iterations / High Fidelity
 Design & Style Guidelines / Copywriting / Presentation Content & Design
- Skills & Technologies Used: User Research (Interviews + Surveys) & Analysis, Persona Creation,
 User Experience Design (UI/UX), Interaction Design, Prototyping, In-Person User Testing, A/B
 Testing, Figma, Miro, InVision, Illustrator, Photoshop.

Education

UX/UI Design Bootcamp Certificate The George Washington University

Feb 2021 – Jul 2021 Washington DC

An intensive 24-week long training in user-centric design research, design thinking, visual prototyping and wireframing, interface design, storyboarding, visual design theory, web prototyping with HTML5 and CSS, interaction design with JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap. Main skills/tools learned consist of Figma, Miro, Invision and Bootstrap.

MA in Communication Design Kingston University

Oct 2012 – Aug 2013 Kingston upon Thames, UK

Three 15-week modules, in an interdisciplinary Postgraduate framework, explored narrative, visual grammar, visual storytelling, interdisciplinary learning, personal development and conceptual thinking. Outcomes were based on visual research undertaken over a 15 week period and covered areas such as typography, layout design, advertising and space.

Main skills learned consists of Indesign, Screen Printing & experimenting on various design fields.